connectionsacademy.com 2018-10-13

# Privacy Policy | Connections Education

_Last Updated: January 24, 2018_

Connections Education LLC, dba Pearson Online & Blended Learning K-12 USA, and its affiliates (collectively, "Connections"), a part of the global learning company, Pearson, respects your privacy and has established this privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") to let you know how we collect, use, manage, share, and protect information that we may gather when you visit our website, the websites of our affiliated schools, or the websites for either of our Education Management Systems, Connexus® or ROADS® (collectively, the "Websites"), or contact us by phone or other means. This Privacy Policy applies to the Websites where this Privacy Policy is posted and to information we gather from you over the phone, via conventional mail or in person. 

Connections reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time. If we make any material changes to this policy, we will post any revised Privacy Policy on the Websites. The most current version is always available by clicking on the "Privacy Policy" link located at the bottom of the Websites’ home page. Any changes to our Privacy Policy will become effective upon posting of the revised Privacy Policy. **By using any of the Websites, you agree to the terms of the Privacy Policy in effect at the time of use. If you do not agree to the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy, please do not use any of the Websites.**

## Information We Collect

We collect two types of information: (1) non-personally identifiable information that is routinely gathered as users navigate through a Website and (2) personally identifiable information voluntarily supplied by you. 

## Non-U.S. Users

The Websites are hosted and operated in the United States and are subject to United States law. Any personal information that you provide to us is being provided to us in the United States and will be hosted on United States servers. You consent to the transfer of your personal information to the United States in order to receive services from Connections. If you are accessing a Website from outside the United States, please be advised that United States law may not offer the same privacy protections as the law of your jurisdiction. 

## Non-Personally Identifiable Information

Each time you visit a Website, information is automatically gathered such as your IP address, domain name, the name of the page from which you entered the Website, which pages you view, and for how long you view them. This information is collected in order to improve the Website, remarketing and for trend analysis. As with most websites, we may use "cookies" for marketing purposes, to track usage, and to improve your experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web page server. The cookies do not collect any personally identifiable information. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If, however, you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of our Websites or have some of our services on the Websites function properly. Further information about cookies is available using the help function of your Internet browser. 

We may use third-party cookies as part of remarketing activities we conduct with Google and/or other third- party vendors, to help provide you with relevant messaging as you use the Internet. As part of these remarketing activities, these third-party cookies may record your visits to our Websites and web sites visited prior. Such cookies can then be used to serve targeted messaging to you on other websites. You may choose to be exempt from the use of Google remarketing cookies at the [Google advertising privacy page](http://www.google.com/privacy/ads/). 

Alternatively, you may opt-out of remarketing on the Google network and similar networks at the [Network Advertising Initiative opt out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp). Opting out will not prevent advertisements from being served to you on the Internet; it will only affect advertisements that utilize remarketing cookies to serve messaging on the specified networks. We are not responsible for the activities of other parties that may not comply with your opt-out requests. 

Because non-personally identifiable information does not identify you, we reserve the right to use it for any purpose and to share it with third parties for any purpose. Please note that to the extent any non-personally identifiable information is combined with personally identifiable information, the combined information will be treated as personally identifiable information for as long as it is so combined. 

## Personally Identifiable Information

##### Parent and Student Users Only

Your school has designated OBL a school official as defined by the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA). For a full explanation of your rights under FERPA please see the [FERPA Notice](https://www.connectionsacademy.com/ferpa-notice "Family Education Rights and Privacy Act"). To the extent that there is an inconsistency between this policy and the FERPA Notice, FERPA controls. 

##### All Users

We may collect personally identifiable information you provide voluntarily when requesting information, catalogs, enrollment, or other materials or to satisfy other requests. This information may include your first and last name, postal address, email address, telephone number and the names, date(s) of birth and grade level(s) of your child(ren). We may also collect credit card information from you. 

Connections uses personally identifiable information voluntarily supplied by you to fulfill requests for information, deliver services to you or for your school, or to carry out the transactions you or your school have requested. For example, if you register for a Connections Academy school using a Website, information will be collected about you and your child(ren) in order to process your registration. This information will be included in Connexus®. Enrollment information that is collected in this manner may be provided to school districts or other third parties as required by state law, federal law, and/or school operating procedures. Similarly, if you participate in a virtual learning program through your school and the school has contracted with Connections to utilize ROADS® in connection with the school’s virtual learning program, personally identifiable information about you will be input into ROADS® by you and/or your school to facilitate the provision of virtual learning services to you. 

Connections may also use personally identifiable information to communicate special messaging, new services, or upcoming events, to provide educational services to students and to otherwise support students, parents, legal guardians, and staff and/or your school with regard to matters such as academic progress, testing, attendance, customer service, or to share information with you related to legislative or regulatory initiatives that could potentially benefit or threaten virtual education in your state, to invite you to share your experience with virtual education, or in the event of an emergency. By providing your mobile number you consent to receive communications by way of pre-recorded and/or autodialed calls. The information will be treated confidentially within Connections, in the same way that we protect other such confidential information. 

We may share personally identifiable information within our affiliated companies and certain service providers. They will use this information to process transactions you have requested, provide customer service and inform you of products or services we offer that you may find useful. Our service providers may include consultants, vendors and companies that perform marketing services on our behalf. We require our service providers to protect your personally identifiable information and to use or disclose it only for the work they are performing for us, or as permitted by law. 

Connexus® and ROADS® contain personally identifiable information that is maintained and accessible by third parties (such as service providers, content partners or vendors). These third parties are provided access to the minimum amount of information required to allow them to perform the tasks for which they have been engaged. Such third parties have agreed to maintain the confidentiality of such information and to use or disclose it only for the work they are performing for us, or as permitted by law. Additionally, Connexus® and ROADS® contain "student educational records" that will be protected by Connections in accordance with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act ("FERPA") and applicable state laws, and we will only retain and disclose educational records or provide access to them in compliance with applicable law. 

If you do not want to receive information unrelated to your enrollment in the school via email from Connections, you can email us at [unsubscribe@connectionseducation.com](mailto:%20unsubscribe@connectionseducation.com) to be excluded from receiving emails from Connections. If you do not want to receive any further information from Connections you can also call us at [877-550-1115](tel:+18775501115 "Contact Us") and ask to be removed from all of Connections’ contact lists. 

In the event that all or substantially all of Connections’ assets are sold or transferred to another party, your personally identifiable information may be transferred to the acquiring entity. However, Connections will take steps to assure that the personally identifiable information is conveyed lawfully and in a manner consistent with the privacy policy under which it was collected. 

Finally, we may disclose your personally identifiable information to third parties if we believe we are required to do so in order to comply with law (including court orders and subpoenas); to comply with lawful requests from law enforcement agencies or other governmental organizations; to enforce our Terms of Use; to protect the rights, privacy, safety, or property of Connections, our affiliated schools, our employees, or other users of the Websites; and/or to permit us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain. We otherwise exercise commercially reasonable care to not otherwise share or disclose the names of users or any other personally-identifying information with third-parties, except with your prior approval and in compliance with federal and state law. 

## Message Boards/Discussion Threads

We may offer message boards, or discussion threads through Connexus® or other education management platform. We may also offer LiveLesson sessions; the Connections virtual classroom environment. Please remember that anyone may read your postings on a message board or discussion thread, or view LiveLesson session content. Furthermore, any information you submit to a message board, or discussion thread, or comments (verbal or in a chat pod) included in a LiveLesson session, will then be disclosed and available to all users of that message board, discussion thread or LiveLesson session and is therefore no longer private or protected. We do not guarantee the security of such information that you disclose or communicate online in public areas such as message boards, discussion threads and in LiveLesson sessions. Therefore, all postings or discussion threads made by you or with which you participate are at your own risk. 

## Children Under 13

Connections is concerned about the safety and privacy of children online. We take reasonable efforts to comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA). 

The Websites are not intended to solicit information of any kind from children under the age of 13, and we do not and will not knowingly contact or collect personally identifiable information from children under 13. The only personal information we receive about children under the age of 13 is information provided by the parent or legal guardian or information provided by the child as part of that child’s participation in a course or courses as part of that child’s K - 12 education program. By enrolling a child in such course or courses, a parent is consenting to the collection of that information. 

It is possible that by fraud or deception by others we may receive information pertaining to children under the age of 13. If we are notified of the receipt of information under such circumstances, once verified, we will promptly obtain parental or guardian consent, and in the absence of such consent, will delete the information. If you want to notify us that we have inadvertently received information for a child under the age of 13, please do so by emailing us at [privacy@connectionseducation.com](mailto:%20privacy@connectionseducation.com). 

You can request to review, edit, or prohibit personally identifiable information of a child under the age of 13 from being used by Connections, its affiliates, schools, and vendors acting on behalf of Connections by making a request in writing to [privacy@connectionseducation.com](mailto:%20privacy@connectionseducation.com). Please note that if you make a request to prohibit personally identifiable information being used by Connections, its affiliates, schools, and vendors acting on behalf of Connections, your child may no longer continue to be enrolled in Connections and this may terminate his or her participation in the Connections program. 

For information on our use of information covered by COPPA please contact us at the following: 

Connections Education LLC  
10960 Grantchester Way  
Columbia, MD 21044  
Phone: [1-800-382-6010](tel:+18003826010 "Contact Us")  
Email: [privacy@connectionseducation.com](mailto:%20privacy@connectionseducation.com)

## Security

Connections takes reasonable steps to safeguard the personally identifiable information you provide. As effective as our safeguards are, no security system is completely impenetrable, so we cannot guarantee the absolute security of our database and systems, nor can we guarantee that personally identifiable information you supply will not be intercepted while being transmitted to us over the Internet. 

## Links

The Websites contain links to other websites or other resources that are provided for your convenience. Such links, unless explicitly stated, are not endorsed by Connections. The information practices of those websites are not covered by this Privacy Policy or any other policies or terms applicable to the Websites. We recommend that you review any terms of use and privacy policies of any third party website linked to the Websites before providing any information to those websites or using their products and services. 

## California Privacy Policies

##### California’s "Shine the Light" law

California residents have the right to receive disclosures about any sharing of their personally identifiable information with third parties for use by the third party as part of their own marketing, and your choices with respect to such disclosures. Because we do not share your personal information with third parties for their own marketing use except as permitted by the Shine the Light law, we are exempt from having to meet this requirement; provided that in the event we elect to share personal information for such purposes in the future, we will secure your consent as required by the Shine the Light law. If you still wish to learn more about our compliance with this requirement, you may send an email to [privacy@connectionseducation.com](mailto:%20privacy@connectionseducation.com) with "Request for California Privacy" in the subject line or write to Connections Education LLC, 10960 Grantchester Way, Columbia, MD 21044 Attn: Legal. 

##### California Do Not Track Disclosures

##### 1\. Online Tracking and Advertising.

We and certain service providers operating on our behalf collect information about your activity on our websites and applications using tracking technologies such as cookies, Flash cookies and Web beacons. Definitions for these tracking technologies, as well as information regarding how to disable them, are available below. This tracking data is used for many purposes including, for example, to: 

  * Provide useful features to simplify your experience when you return to our sites and applications
  * Deliver relevant content based on your preferences, usage patterns and location
  * Monitor and evaluate the use and operation of our sites and applications, including technical information about the device or browser you use to access our sites such as your device's IP address, cookie string data and (in the case of mobile devices) your device type and mobile device's unique identifier such as the Apple IDFA or Android Advertising ID
  * Analyze traffic on our websites, including your browsing activity on our sites, which pages you visited and when
  * Track the online ads we have served (or attempted to serve) to you, including how many times an ad has been served to you, what page the ad appeared on, and whether you clicked on or otherwise interacted with the ad

Tracking data collected by us and our service providers generally does not identify you personally and is not associated with your registration account. Should we associate this tracking data with your registration account, we will treat it as personal information. 

##### 2\. Online Tracking Technologies

Examples of online tracking technologies include: 

  * _Cookies_. Cookies are pieces of information that a website places on the hard drive of your computer when you visit the website. Cookies may involve the transmission of information from us to you and from you directly to us, to another party on our behalf, or to another party in accordance with its privacy policy. We may use cookies to bring together information we collect about you. You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies. If you turn cookies off, you won’t have access to many features that make your guest experience more efficient and some of our services may not function properly.
  * _Flash cookies_. We may use local shared objects, sometimes known as Flash cookies, to store your preferences or display content based upon what you view on our site to personalize your visit. Our third-party service providers also may use Flash cookies to collect and store information. Flash cookies are different from browser cookies because of the amount of, type of, and how data is stored. Cookie management tools provided by your browser will not remove Flash cookies. Learn how to [manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html). If you disable Flash cookies, you won’t have access to many features that make your guest experience more efficient and some of our services may not function properly.
  * _Web beacons_. Web beacons are small pieces of data that are embedded in images on the pages of sites. Web beacons may involve the transmission of information directly to us, to another party on our behalf, or to another party in accordance with its privacy policy. We may use web beacons to bring together information we collect about your browsing behavior.

##### 3\. Do Not Track

You can opt-out of our tracking your online activity for targeted advertising purposes (Do Not Track): We respond to "do not track" or "DNT" signals sent from your browser. If our websites receive a DNT signal during a visit, we will not link data we collect to your browser identifier so that new data collected about you will not be used by us for targeted advertising purposes, but older data collected about you may still be used. You may [choose not to receive targeted advertising from us and our service providers](http://www.aboutads.info/choices). To opt-out of tracking by us you should select "AdRoll" and follow the directions on this site. If you opt-out we may still collect some data about your online activity for operational purposes. 

Currently, there are various browsers (such as Internet Explorer, Firefox and Safari) that offer a DNT option that allows you to set the DNT signal on your browser so that third-party sites know you do not want to be tracked. For more information on DNT or information on how to set the DNT setting in your browser, go to the Do Not Track website: <http://donottrack.us/>. 

##### Contact Information

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us by email at [privacy@connectionseducation.com](mailto:%20privacy@connectionseducation.com). Please note that email communications will not necessarily be secure. Accordingly, you should not include sensitive information in your email correspondence with us.
